Guide to the Department of History, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, circa 1940-1987; Accession 1997-A-080
  - Educational equality project, teaching in America, and education, 1980-1990 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - University Advisory Council on the Yale-New Haven Teachers Institute, 1985-1986 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Yale - New Haven Teachers Institute (parts I and II), 1970-1984 (Box 21, Folder 27-28)
  - A.H.A. History education project, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Yale - New Haven Teachers Institute and endowment data, 1978-1988 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Teachers Institute curriculum vitae, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Yale History appointments, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Douglass papers budget, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities budget form, 1987-1989 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Frederick Douglass papers, proposal for a biographical dictionary of Afro-Americans. (parts I through VIII), 1971-1988 (Box 22, Folder 4-11)
  - AHA annual meeting, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Franklin papers, 1969-1972 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Parliamentary diaries project, 1964-1967 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Political Science research library, 1968-1976 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Political Science research library, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - German war crimes trials, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - German foreign ministry documents, 1963-1970 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Fourth International Congress on the Enlightenment, July 1975 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Conference on "Change in Contemporary Southern Africa", 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Conference on France and Britain in Africa, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Conference on British and German colonialism, March 22-26, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - America week, Munich, June 19-24, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Conference on Russian foreign policy, April 6-8, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Mellon gift, 1967-1970 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Yale draft deferment policy, July 1968 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Governance, 1969-1971 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Administration, agenda, department meetings, 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Administration notices to members of department, 1944-1953 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Administration committees, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Administration minutes, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Administration, agenda, department meetings, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Administration minutes, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Administration minutes of departmental meetings, 1945-1950 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Administration minutes of departmental meetings, 1940-1944 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Administration, minutes of meetings, graduate school, 1934-1949 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Administration, agenda, department meetings, graduate (final meetings of the year), 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Administration correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Administration, division, general, 1949-1953 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Administration, general, 1954-1956 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Administration, correspondence and odd information, 1954-1956 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Administration correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Administration, correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Administration, correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - Administration, correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - Administration, correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Administration, correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Administration, correspondence, 1936-1946 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Personnel, non-faculty, readers, 1954-1962 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Budget calculations, 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - History budget, 1961-1962 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - History budget, 1960-1961 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - History budget, 1959-1960 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Administration, budget, 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - History budget, 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Report of departmental committee on teaching fellows, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Budget for teaching by graduate students, 1982-1983 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Part-time acting instructors, 1982-1983 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Teaching fellows, 1982-1983 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Prize teaching fellowship, 1981-1982 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Teaching fellow guidelines and budget (including acting instructor), 1981-1982 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Teaching fellows, 1981-1982 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Teaching fellow budget and needs, 1980-1981 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Teaching fellows, 1980-1981 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Part-time acting instructors and teaching fellows: salaries and funds, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Teaching fellows, 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Teaching fellows, 1978-1979 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Teaching fellows, 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Teaching fellows, spring, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Teaching fellows, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Teaching fellows, fall, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Teaching fellows, summer term, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 2A)
  - Teaching fellows, 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Teaching fellows, second semester, 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Teaching fellows, first term, 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Teaching fellows and assistants in instruction (readers), 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Teaching fellows, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Teaching fellows, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Teaching fellows, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Teaching fellows, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Teaching fellows, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Adminstration, notices to members of department, 1953-1956 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Administration, minutes, 1953-1956 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Administration, minutes, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Administration, report to president, 1950-1956 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Administration, report to president, 1948-1950 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Administration, special report to president, April 17, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Administration, reports of department, 1928-1946 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Administration, committees, educational planning, 1937-1941 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Teaching fellows, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Teaching fellows, 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Assistants in instruction, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Assistants in instruction, 1966-1967 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Assistants in instruction, 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Assistants in instruction, policy, stipends, 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Assistants in instruction (readers), 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Assistants in instruction (readers), 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Assistants in instruction (readers), 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Assistants in instruction (readers), 1970-1971 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Assistants in instruction (readers), 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Readers, 1968-1969 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript etc... typists, 1967-1972 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Departmental lunch assistants, 1969-1974 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Fair labor standard act reports, 1968-1972 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Yale student payroll, 1962-1964 (Box 25, Folder 6A)
  - Yale student payroll (readers) (parts I and II), 1957-1968 (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
  - Lists of readers for undergraduate courses, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Wage and salary administration, 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Wage and salary administration, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Wage and salary administration, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Wage and salary administration, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Fair labor standard act reports and attendance records, 1973-1978 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Yale reception, Sheraton Hotel, December 29, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Yale reception, New York Hilton, December 29, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Yale reception, San Francisco, Hilton Hotel, December 29, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Yale reception, Dallas, Fairmont Hotel, December 28, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Yale reception, Washington, Sheraton, Park Hotel, December 29, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Yale reception, Atlanta, Marriott Motor Hotel, December 29, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Yale reception, Chicago, Conrad Hilton, December 28, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - New England Historical Association, 1971-1979 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Yale reception, San Francisco Hilton Hotel, December 29, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Yale reception, Royal Sonesta (New Orleans), December 29, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Yale Smoker, Statler Hilton Hotel, December 28, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Yale Smoker, Sheraton, Boston Hotel, December 29, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Yale Smoker, Sheraton Park Hotel, December 29, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - AHA, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Announcements of the first meeting of the year, and other general matters, 1973-1976 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Yale College, special programs, budget credits, 1972-1974 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - History of higher education, foundation prospects, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Junior faculty and summer stipends, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Junior faculty summer research support, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Junior faculty summer research support, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Junior faculty summer research support, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Junior faculty summer research support, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Junior faculty summer research support, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Junior faculty summer research support, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Junior faculty summer research support, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Summer research support, 1964-1966 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - Lectures (including visitors), 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 43)
  - Lectures, 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Lectures, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - Lectures, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - Lectures committee, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 47)
  - Guest lectures, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - Lectures committee, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - Lectures, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 50)
  - Guest lectures, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - Lectures, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 52)
  - Lectures, 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 53)
  - Lectures, 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 54)
  - Lectures, 1971-1972 (Box 25, Folder 56)
  - Lectures, 1967-1968 (Box 25, Folder 57)
  - Lectures, 1965-1966 (Box 25, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 59)
  - Yale Historical Bulletin, September, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 60)
  - Maps, 1968-1969 (Box 25, Folder 62)
  - "Guests" of the department, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 64)
  - Manuscript typists (parts I and II), 1968-1986 (Box 25, Folder 65-66)
  - History lunch attendant, 1975-1979 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Individual salaries and wages, 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Individual salaries and wages, 1981-1982 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Individual salaries and wages, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Individual salaries and wages, 1979-1980 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Individual salaries and wages, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Individual salaries and wages, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Individual salaries and wages, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Individual salaries and wages, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - India, old possibilities, University of Pennsylvania, etc..., 1959-1962 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Report on India, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Southeast Asia, 1979-1980 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Southeast Asian History, 1972-1975 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Yale and two S.E.A. universities, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Russian and East European studies, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Russian History, staffing, 1965-1967 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Chinese History, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Yung Wing - Nelson Wu, etc., 1954 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Personnel, faculty, Chinese History, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Personnel, faculty, Far Eastern History, 1944-1945 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - China, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - China boys, 1957-1958 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - M.A. degree in Afro-American studies, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Program in international relations, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Applicants for jobs at Yale, 1956-1957 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Applicants for jobs at Yale, 1955-1956 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Personnel, Africa, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Personnel, American History (asst. prof), 1952-1956 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Faculty, American History, 1952-1956 (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - Personnel, faculty, Balkans, Undated (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Personnel, faculty, English History, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Personnel, faculty, European History, 1952-1956 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Personnel, faculty, Medieval History, 1951-1956 (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - Personnel, faculty, Renaissance and Reformation, 1955-1956 (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - Personnel, faculty, History of Science, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - Personnel, faculty, visiting fellowships, 1951-1952 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - Personnel, faculty, visiting professors, Undated (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - Personnel, faculty, visiting lecturers, 1955-1956 (Box 26, Folder 43A)
  - Faculty, possible personnel, 1955-1956 (Box 26, Folder 44)
  - Personnel, non-faculty, clerical, 1953-1955 (Box 26, Folder 45)
  - Personnel, non-faculty, bursary, 1954-1957 (Box 26, Folder 46)
  - Personnel, general, 1938-1946 (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - Personnel (possible), Latin American History, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - Faculty, possible personnel, 1953-1955 (Box 26, Folder 49)
  - Personnel, possible personnel, 1953-1954 (Box 26, Folder 50)
  - Personnel, faculty, possible personnel, 1952-1953 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Personnel, faculty, possible personnel, 1951-1952 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Personnel, faculty, possible personnel, 1950-1951 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Personnel, faculty, possible personnel, 1949-1950 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Personnel, faculty, possible personnel, 1948-1949 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Personnel, faculty, possible personnel, 1947-1948 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Personnel, faculty, possible personnel, 1946-1947 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Personnel, faculty, Latin American candidates, 1942-1945 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Personnel, faculty, medieval candidates, 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Personnel, non-faculty, readers, 1936-1952 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Personnel, faculty, possible personnel, 1945-1946 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Personnel, non-faculty, clerical, 1939-1953 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Personnel, non-faculty, bursary, 1941-1955 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous (parts I and II), 1964-1968 (Box 27, Folder 14-15)
  - Department, not vital, 1965-1967 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Policy statements in administration, 1966-1967 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Blum, John M., correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 27, Folder 17A)
  - Deans, Provost, general, 1961-1966 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Faculty hires and tenure, 1964-1966 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Property and equipment budget, 1962-1966 (Box 27, Folder 19A)
  - Accepted appointments, Yale news, 1960-1961 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Undergraduate courses, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - African history, 1967-1968 (Box 27, Folder 22A)
  - Library problems, 1967-1968 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - American studies, reports and business, 1967-1968 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Appointments, 1963-1964 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Fellowships, grants, 1962-1964 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Appointments (parts I, II, and III), 1963-1964 (Box 27, Folder 28-30)
  - Advisory committee, division of the Social Sciences, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - African History, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - American History committee, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - American studies, 1968-1969 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Canadian History, bibliography, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Comparative History, Undated (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Culler report, graduate programs in the Humanities, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Faculty, personnel, and additions, 1968-1971 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Appointment possibilities, 1965-1969 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - European History (parts I, II, and III), 1966-1969 (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
  - History of the community, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1955-1956 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Administration (budget), bills and receipts, 1955-1956 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Budget, 1954-1955 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Administration (budget), bills and receipts, 1954-1955 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Bills and receipts, budget, 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Administration (budget), bills and receipts, 1952-1953 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Administration budget, 1952-1953 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Administration budget, 1951-1952 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Budget, 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Budgets previous, 1934-1939 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Budgets, 1941-1952 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Administration (budget), bills and receipts, 1951-1952 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Administration (budget), bills and receipts, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Administration, budget, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Administration, budget, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Administration, budget, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Administration, budget, 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Administration, budget, 1946-1947 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Administration, budget, 1945-1946 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Administration, budget, 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Administration, general, plans, 1942-1946 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Russian History, 1965-1966 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - International studies, 1961, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Committee on Non-Western International Studies (CONWIS), ten year planning, 1960-1962 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - C.O.N.W.I.S. position papers, 1958-1960 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - C.O.N.W.I.S. minutes, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Foreign area studies, 1947-1960 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Yale fellows in East Asian studies, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - South East Asian studies, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Personnel, faculty, Near Eastern History, 1950-1960 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Near East Africa, 1957-1960 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Japanese History, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Conference on Russian foreign relations, 1959-1961 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Russian foreign policy, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Executive committee, Russian studies, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Russian studies, Yale courses, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Billlington, 1957-1961 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Russian, Slavic library, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Russian Studies, 1958-1959 (Box 29, Folder 16A)
  - Foundation, Russia, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Russia, title VI, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Russian studies, spring, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Russia, major correspondence, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Russian studies programs elsewhere, 1956-1959 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Yale Russian studies, October 30, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Old budget, 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Final budget, 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Budget, 1967-1968 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Budget, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Budget, 1966-1967 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Budget instructions, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Budget, working materials and draft (parts I, II, and III), 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 32-34)
  - Budget, 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Budget, 1963-1964 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Budget, draft, and directions, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Budget (parts I and II), 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 6-7)
  - Billings memorial awards, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Morse fellowships, 1960-1961 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Administration, Morse fellowships, 1956-1959 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Teaching fellowships, 1957-1961 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - (The) Danforth foundation, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Hatch prize, 1960-1971 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - John Hay fellows program, 1958-1967 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Commonwealth, 1958-1962 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Scholarships and fellowships openings; Brown, Stimson, Guggenheim, 1956-1961 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - St. Paul's, Exeter, other schools, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Prize competitions outside, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Woodrow Wilson fellowships, 1955-1968 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous prizes, 1959-1961 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Department memorabilia, 1962-1967 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Bulletin, copy and correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - History department bulletin, 1944-1965 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Yale historical bulletin, 1943-1963 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Yale historical bulletin, 1961-1965 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Yale health bulletin, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Bulletin, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Use of History, 1960-1961 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Letters on Yale History Bulletin, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Yale History Bulletin, April 1960 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Bulletin, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Bulletin articles for brochure, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin, manuscripts and correspondence, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Administration bulletin, 1943-1948 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Administration bulletin, 1949-1951 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Yale press, 1961-1962 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Yale press (parts I and II), 1958-1961 (Box 31, Folder 10-10A)
  - Yale historical publications, 1961-1962 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Yale historical publications, lists and policy statement, duplicates, etc..., 1951-1960 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - News, news bureau releases, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Master of Arts in Teaching (M.A.T), 1958-1961 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Master of Arts in teaching, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Methods of training college teachers, February 3, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Fifteenth Yale Conference on the Teaching of Social Studies, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Yale Conference on Teaching of the Social Studies, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Fifth Yale conference on teaching Social Studies, 1960-1970 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Summer session secondary school teachers and master of arts in teaching, 1951-1957 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Advanced placement, 1959-1961 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Advanced placement committee, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Advanced placement, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Advanced placement, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Yale advanced placement conference, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - A.H.A. (Toronto), 1967-1969 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - A.H.A., 1965 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Yale Smoker, Sheraton Park Hotel, Washington, December 29, 1961-1966 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Yale Smoker, Statler Hilton Hotel, N.Y., December 29, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - A.H.A., 1961-1962 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - A.H.A., 1959-1962 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - American Historical Association, 1956-1967 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Administration, American Historical Association, 1952-1958 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - American Association of University professors, 1961-1962 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - American History Association (AHA) program, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 3A)
  - Medieval studies, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 4A)
  - Mississippi rally, 1958-1962 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - New England Association of Social Studies Teachers, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 5A)
  - Franco-American colloquium, 1960-1961 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Society for French Historical studies, 1958-1962 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Society of French Historical studies, 1956-1962 (Box 32, Folder 7A)
  - Western America, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Amerika, Woche, Munich, 1961-1962 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Professional societies, America week, notes of meetings minutes, 1956-1958 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Professional societies, America week, Denys Hay, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Professional societies, America week, N.G.D. Joarder, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Professional societies, America week, Kolko, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - History department: policy documents, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Department plans and general, 1958-1962 (Box 32, Folder 16)